Reece Thatcher

Cannon Rd. N17 8FE *********

reecethat@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

Portfolio

PERSONAL PROFILE

With over a year of experience as a Front-end Developer at Saville Assessment, I've updated their assessment platform's front-end, tackling projects for new features, page design, and UX/UI upgrades. Holding a Level 5 Diploma in Full-Stack Web Development from the Code Institute, I excel in SCSS, JavaScript, Python, C#, .NET, React, Flask, and Django, maintaining a focus on clean code and best coding practices.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer — Saville Assessment.

Jan 2023 - To Date

- Developed cutting-edge front-end features for the assessment platform, crafting modern, user-centric pages using C#, .NET and SCSS whilst collaborating seamlessly with backend developers.
- Utilized Figma to create detailed wireframes, ensuring precise blueprints for new features.
- Completed 15 substantial projects in a year, breaking each project into manageable components.
- Implemented Microsoft Azure for robust version control, ensuring seamless collaboration and efficient management of project versions across the development lifecycle

Tech Trainee — futureproof, Artillery Row, London

JUNE 2022 - SEPT 2022

- Worked with **JavaScript**, **Python**, **React**, **Django** and **Flask** to build various fullstack projects.
- Worked collaboratively to produce projects using GitHub for version control.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development Diploma Level 5 — Code Institute

JULY 2021 - JULY 2022

- Divided into 5 milestone projects, demonstrating the use of **Python**, **JavaScript**, **Jest**, **Flask**, **Materialize**, **Bootstrap** and **JQuery**.
- Achieved a Merit grade for my Full-Stack project.

Physics BSc — Queen Mary University

SEPT 2016 - OCT 2019

- Simulated particle collisions using C++, during my final year project.
- Analyzed Higgs Boson Properties and Interactions by comparing the simulations to Real-World Data.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CSS/HTML

Python

JavaScript

C#

JQuery

Sass

Bootstrap

Materialize

Jest

Unittest

Django

Flask

React

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Figma (Wireframing)

Version Control (Git)

Microsoft Azure

LANGUAGES

English Native

Japanese

Basic - Intermediate

Modern Greek

Basic

A-Levels — Battersea Park School

JULY 2012 - JULY 2014

A* to A grade in Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Further Mathematics, and Business.

PROJECTS

<u>Trial by Trivia</u> — Code Institute

- A trivia application with a twist. Users can play in single or multiplayer mode, where each question is timed, and users can choose from varying categories and difficulties.
- **JavaScript** is the main language used for the project, the **React** library is also used in the front-end for reuse of components. **Jest** was used for testing.
- Docker was used for containerisation for the backend
- The application also retrieves data from the **Trivia API**.
- Deployment of application with **Netlify**.

TwigElites — futureproof

- A locator application, to locate the original Twiglets as they were recently banned.
- With full CRUD functionality, a user can add the location of original Twiglets still being sold around the world.
- Designed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python languages, Flask framework for the backend, PostgreSQL for the DB and React library for the frontend.
- The **Google Maps API** was also utilized for retrieving location data to store in the backend.
- GitHub was used for version control and Netlify and Heroku for deployment..

SOFT SKILLS

Creative Thinking

Logical Thinking

Detail-Oriented

Adaptable

Communication

Time-Management

Autodidactic

INTERESTS

Animation

Illustration